# Sarah El-Dawody

7 Moez Eldawla, Nasr City, Cairo, Egypt

Mobile Number: (+20)1127736099 - (+20) 1061998422

Home Number: (+20)0222732898 Hotmail: saraheldawody@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarah-el-dawody-3484b8b3">https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarah-el-dawody-3484b8b3</a>
Upwork: <a href="https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~0103bbedac2796c5df">https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~0103bbedac2796c5df</a>

Freelancer: <a href="https://www.freelancer.com/u/saraheldawody">https://www.freelancer.com/u/saraheldawody</a>

Fiverr: https://www.fiverr.com/saraheldawody

Blogger: https://www.blogger.com/profile/01206858609031688817

Github: https://github.com/saraheldawody

# **PERSONAL STATEMENT**

I have over 4 years of experience working in Software Development Field. I've worked as a freelancer software engineer for more than 2 years. I mastered software development using .Net Technology and using Python. I've done several projects in this field as a freelancer and when I worked as a software developer in office. I also started working in data science field recently beside software engineering using python and I've worked in database development using PostgreSQL, MS SQL, and MySQL.

Date of Birth: 27, September, 1992

Languages: Arabic and English

Gmail: seldawody92@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Freelancer Data Scientist

2018 – Present

#### Responsibilities:

- Collecting, organizing and managing data from several data sources.
- Cleaning data and preparing it for Analysis.
- Analyzing Datasets and extracting insights from the data.
- Visualizing data and building dashboards that represents insights and visualizations of the data.
- Building predictive models and training the models on the training data.
- Calculating models accuracy and enhance implemented models to enhance the accuracy.
- Implementing machine learning and deep learning algorithms.
- Freelancer Software Engineer

2016 - Present

#### Responsibilities:

- Analyze, Design and implement software systems.
- Design and implement databases.
- Design and implement web applications.
- Design and implement desktop applications.
- Implementing APIs for several kind of applications.
- Implementing algorithms using python and c# programming languages.
- Building web applications using ASP.NET MVC c#, and Python Flask Framework.
- Implementing Databases using SQL server and PostgreSQL.
- Building Desktop applications using c# windows forms, Python PyQT, and Tkinter.
- Building dynamic reports using Telerik reporting, crystal reports, and sql reporting services.

• Software Engineer at Nebras Technology

2015 - 2016

A Medical care Company located in Giza, Egypt Responsibilities:

- Analyze, Design and implement software systems.
- Design and implement web applications using ASP.NET MVC C#.
- Build database to web applications using Entity Framework code first approach
- Modify existing web applications, solving bugs and adding new features.
- Implementing algorithms and data structures that solve several problems.
- Design web applications pages using HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuiry, Kendo UI, and Bootstrap.
- Designing One Page Web application using Telerik MVVM.
- Building dynamic reports using Telerik reporting.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science from Ain Shams University

Class: 2015 grade: good

High School Certificate Ajyal Al Ma'arfa High School Grade: 96% (math section)

#### AREAS OF INTEREST

- Web development: .Net, Python and MEAN Stack
- Data Science and Data Analysis (Using Python)
- Desktop Applications : Using .Net Framework (C#)
- Software Engineering

#### **QUALIFICATION**

Programming Languages: C/C++, C#, python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON

<u>Frameworks & Libraries:</u> Flask, Dash, ASP.Net,JQuery,AngularJS,NodeJS,ExpressJS, Entity Framework, Bootstrap, AJAX, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, SciPy, Scikit-learn, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, tweepy, TextBlob

<u>Concepts</u>: OOP, Computer Security, General Algorithms, Data Structures, Object oriented, Data Analysis, Data Science, Data Visualization, Data Wrangling, Data Cleansing, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Deep Learning, Neural Network, Database Design, UML Modeling, Big data, Software Engineering, MVC, MVVM.

Database: MS SQL Server, MS Access, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

<u>Tools:</u> Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft Office, Kendo UI, Telerik Reporting, Microsoft Visual Studio, Adobe Dreamwaver, Adobe Photoshop

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Team Worker, Time Committee, Hard worker, Work under high pressure, Self-learning, presentation and Documentation skills

#### **PROJECTS**

#### • Vocabulary Quiz Web Application with Dashboard

Freelance Project

A web application that allow Chinese students to test their level of knowledge for English Vocabulary and shows there parents their progress and their level

Tools used: Python Flask, PostgreSQL DB, Plotly Library for visualizations.

### • Analysing Bus Trajectories GPS data and Building Arrival Time Prediction Model

Freelance Project

Analysing Raw GPS data and getting calculations and insights of the behaviour of the buses and build a model for predicting arrival time using the data analysed to train the model. Tools used: Python, Dash, Plotly, Sckit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, Mapbox, Google Maps APIs, and Google colab

#### • Analysing Trump tweets and Study their impact on the world economy

Freelance Projec

Analyzing Trumps tweets by applying sentiment analysis on it and then study the impact of these tweets on the world economy using US and world stock data.

Tools used: Python, Numpy, Pandas, Tweepy, NLTK, TextBlob and scikit-learn.

#### • Scrapping Events data

Freelance project

Scraping Musical events data from an events website and save the data in CSV file Tools used: Python, Selenium, Beautiful Soup, and pandas

#### Scraping YouTube Videos Data

Freelance Project

Scraping data about videos from youtube and save it in Json Files

Used tools: Python, Selenium, Beautiful Soup, and Pandas

#### • School Management System Web Application

Freelance Project

Web application used to manage School data and activities related to students, teachers and employees.

Tools used: ASP.NET MVC C#, Entity Framework, Visual Studio, SQL Server, Kendo UI, Telerik Reporting.

#### • Attendance Desktop Application

Freelance Project

Desktop Application that helps teachers to record student attendance using there ID.

Tools used: C#, Windows Forms, SQL Server

#### Restaurant Desktop Application

Freelance Project

Desktop Application that manages restaurants and give reports of the business progress.

Tools used: C#, Windows Forms, SQL Server, and Crystal Reports.

#### Video Portal Web Application

Freelance Project

Web application that is a portal for several videos in several categories.

Tools used: MEAN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, Angular.js, and Node.js)

#### Dentalore Cloud

Nebras Technology Project

Web Application for Dentists that manages dentists clinics, patients and employees Tools used: ASP.NET MVC C#, SQL Server, Entity Framework Code First, Kendo UI, Telerik Reporting, Kendo MVVM, Ajax, Json, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Bootstrap.

## • Decision Support System for distribution of medicines in pharmacies

College Project

Desktop application that helps to take a decision to distribute medicines for the right pharmacies that needs this medicines the most.

Tools used: C#, Windows Forms, SQL Server

#### • Search Engine on Web with Web Crawler

College Project

Mini Search Engine with Web Crawler Tools used: ASP.NET C#, SQL Server

# • Graduation Project: Big data Management System(Java):

O Aims to develop computer software that Handle storing big data in database.

O Handling 2 Vs of the dimensions of big data (Volume and Variety) of Big Data and has its own Query Language.

2014-2015